<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rehab | Qian's Group</title><link>https://qiansgroup.github.io/category/rehab/</link><atom:link href="https://qiansgroup.github.io/category/rehab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Rehab</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:15:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://qiansgroup.github.io/media/icon_hu17f5e10f4582494e3190e5ce2ee17e7e_63771_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Rehab</title><link>https://qiansgroup.github.io/category/rehab/</link></image><item><title>Smart Pulmonary Rehabilitation</title><link>https://qiansgroup.github.io/project/pr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:15:46 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://qiansgroup.github.io/project/pr/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pulmonary rehabilitation is important for individuals with chronic respiratory conditions, such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), asthma, pulmonary fibrosis, and others. Here are several reasons why it is important:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Improved Respiratory Function: Pulmonary rehabilitation programs typically include exercises and techniques aimed at improving lung function and respiratory muscle strength. These exercises can help individuals breathe more efficiently, increase lung capacity, and reduce breathlessness during daily activities. By improving respiratory function, pulmonary rehabilitation can enhance overall quality of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Symptom Management: Chronic respiratory conditions often lead to symptoms such as shortness of breath, fatigue, and decreased exercise tolerance. Pulmonary rehabilitation programs provide strategies and techniques to manage these symptoms effectively. Through education, breathing exercises, and energy conservation techniques, individuals can learn how to better cope with their symptoms and carry out daily activities with greater ease.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enhanced Exercise Tolerance: Regular exercise is a key component of pulmonary rehabilitation. Exercise training helps individuals build endurance, strength, and cardiovascular fitness. By gradually increasing physical activity levels under the supervision of healthcare professionals, individuals can improve their exercise tolerance and perform daily activities with less difficulty.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Psychological Well-being: Chronic respiratory conditions can have a significant impact on a person&amp;rsquo;s mental and emotional well-being. Feelings of anxiety, depression, and social isolation are common. Pulmonary rehabilitation programs often include psychological support and counseling to address these issues. By providing a supportive environment and counseling services, individuals can receive emotional support and learn strategies to cope with the psychological challenges associated with their condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Education and Self-Management: Pulmonary rehabilitation programs offer education on the disease process, medications, proper inhaler techniques, and lifestyle modifications. This knowledge empowers individuals to take an active role in managing their condition and make informed decisions about their health. By learning about their condition and how to manage it effectively, individuals can reduce exacerbations, hospitalizations, and improve disease control.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multidisciplinary Approach: Pulmonary rehabilitation involves a multidisciplinary team of healthcare professionals, including pulmonologists, respiratory therapists, physiotherapists, occupational therapists, and psychologists. This collaborative approach ensures that individuals receive comprehensive care addressing their physical, emotional, and social needs. The team works together to create personalized treatment plans tailored to each individual&amp;rsquo;s specific requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Overall, pulmonary rehabilitation plays a crucial role in improving the quality of life for individuals with chronic respiratory conditions. It helps individuals regain and maintain their functional abilities, manage symptoms effectively, and enhance their overall well-being. If you or someone you know has a chronic respiratory condition, it is advisable to consult a healthcare professional to determine if pulmonary rehabilitation is appropriate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Related publications:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>[IMWUT/UbiComp ’23] Wentao Xie, Qingyong Hu, Jin Zhang, Qian Zhang, “EarSpiro: Earphone-based Spirometry for Lung Function Assessment”, Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies, 6 (4), 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>[IoTJ ’20] Wentao Xie, Runxin Tian, Jin Zhang, Qian Zhang, “Noncontact Respiration Detection Leveraging Music and Broadcast Signals”, IEEE Internet of Things Journal, 8 (4), 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>